Application and Admissions Publications UP027
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Application and Admissions Publications
1897 -- 2019
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Tufts University
Office of Undergraduate Admissions
UP027
2.25 Linear Feet
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into three series: Undergraduate School of Arts, Sciences and Engineering; Graduate School of Arts and Sciences; and the School of Dental Medicine.
Biographical / Historical
Since 1955, Tufts University has continued to expand its horizons. In 1964, in one of Wessell's final acts as president, Tufts opened the Experimental College. The Ex-College, which allows students to take classes not normally found in the curriculum, has remained one of Tufts' most popular programs.
In 1977, Tufts established a five-year joint degree program with the New England Conservatory of Music. Soon after, in 1979, a similar program began with the School of the Museum of Fine Arts. Also in 1979, the Tufts Center for European Studies in Talloires, France, was established in an 11th Century priory. The Tufts European Center began operation soon after.
In late 1979, Tufts made another important addition. In October, the Tufts University School of Veterinary Medicine opened at its original Boston campus. In 1980, the Grafton campus, built on the site of a state mental hospital, officially opened its doors.
The last two major additions to Tufts University took place in 1980 and 1981. In 1980, the Sackler School of Graduate Biomedical Sciences, established with a large grant from the Sackler family, opened its doors on the Boston campus of the Tufts School of Medicine. In 1981, at the Medford Campus, Tufts celebrated the opening of the School of Nutrition Science and Policy. The school was the first of its kind in the nation.
Since Tufts College was officially established in 1852, it has continued to grow and expand in new directions. From its beginnings as a small liberal arts college through its expansion into a full-scale university, Tufts has maintained a strong academic tradition and a community feel.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains admissions bulletins printed for prospective Tufts students. Publications can include school information and highlights, department listings, admissions procedures and requirements, financial aid information, school maps, and a copy of the application.
- Undergraduate School of Arts, Sciences and Engineering, 1897 -- 2019; 1897 -- 2009; UP027.001; 1.7 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains admissions bulletins printed for prospective Tufts School of Arts and Sciences undergraduate students. Publications can include school information and highlights, department listing, admissions procedures and requirements, financial aid information, school maps, and application. Tufts admissions publication renamed to "Jumbo" in 2011.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Tufts College: Its Location and Surroundings, Opportunities for Students, and Terms of Admissions, 1897; UP027.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Tufts College: Its Location and Surroundings, Opportunities for Students, and Terms of Admissions, 1898; UP027.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Tufts College A Seat of Learning in New England, 1921; UP027.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Tufts College A Seat of Learning in New England, 1931; UP027.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Tufts College A Seat of Learning in New England, 1935; UP027.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Tufts College A Seat of Learning in New England, 1938; UP027.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Bulletin of Tufts: Colleges of Liberal Arts and Engineering, 1950; UP027.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Tufts College of Liberal Arts and Engineering, 1952; UP027.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - Tufts College School of Liberal Arts: Handbook for Propsective Tufts Students, 1953; UP027.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - Tufts College School of Liberal Arts: Handbook for Propsective Tufts Students, 1954; UP027.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - Tufts College School of Liberal Arts and College of Engineering: Handbook for Propsective Tufts Students, 1948 -- 1952; UP027.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - Tufts College School of Liberal Arts and College of Engineering: Handbook for Propsective Tufts Students, 1956; UP027.001.00012 (Box 1)
  - Tufts College School of Liberal Arts and College of Engineering: Handbook for Propsective Tufts Students, 1956; UP027.001.00013 (Box 1)
  - Here is Jackson: A Liberal Arts College for Women, 1959; UP027.001.00014 (Box 1)
  - Tufts School of Liberal Arts and Engineering at Medford, 1956; UP027.001.00015 (Box 1)
  - Bulletin of Tufts University: Prospective Students, 1964; UP027.001.00016 (Box 1)
  - Bulletin of Tufts University: Prospective Students, 1965; UP027.001.00017 (Box 1)
  - Bulletin of Tufts University: Prospective Students, 1967 -- 1969; UP027.001.00018 (Box 1)
  - Bulletin of Tufts University: Prospective Students, 1968 -- 1970; UP027.001.00019 (Box 1)
  - Bulletin of Tufts University: Prospective Students, 1970 -- 1971; UP027.001.00020 (Box 1)
  - Bulletin of Tufts University: Prospective Students, 1971 -- 1972; UP027.001.00021 (Box 1)
  - Bulletin of Tufts University: Prospective Students, 1972 -- 1973; UP027.001.00022 (Box 1)
  - Bulletin of Tufts University: Prospective Students, 1973 -- 1974; UP027.001.00023 (Box 1)
  - Bulletin of Tufts University: Prospective Students, 1974 -- 1975; UP027.001.00024 (Box 1)
  - Bulletin of Tufts University: Prospective Students, 1975 -- 1976; UP027.001.00025 (Box 1)
  - Tufts University: Prospective Students, 1976 -- 1977; UP027.001.00026 (Box 1)
  - Bulletin of Tufts University, 1977 -- 1978; UP027.001.00027 (Box 1)
  - Bulletin of Tufts University, 1978 -- 1979; UP027.001.00028 (Box 1)
  - Bulletin of Tufts University, 1979 -- 1980; UP027.001.00029 (Box 1)
  - Bulletin of Tufts University, 1981 -- 1982; UP027.001.00030 (Box 1)
  - Bulletin of Tufts University, 1983 -- 1984; UP027.001.00031 (Box 1)
  - Bulletin of Tufts University, 1985 -- 1986; UP027.001.00032 (Box 1)
  - Bulletin of Tufts University, 1986 -- 1987; UP027.001.00033 (Box 1)
  - Bulletin of Tufts University, 1987 -- 1988; UP027.001.00034 (Box 1)
  - Bulletin of Tufts University, 1988 -- 1989; UP027.001.00035 (Box 1)
  - Bulletin of Tufts University, 1989 -- 1990; UP027.001.00036 (Box 1)
  - Exploring Tufts, 1989 -- 1990; UP027.001.00037 (Box 1)
  - Exploring Tufts, 1992 -- 1993; UP027.001.00038 (Box 1)
  - Tufts: a light on the hill, 1993; UP027.001.00039 (Box 1)
  - Tufts University: The Class of 1998, 1993; UP027.001.00040 (Box 1)
  - Exploring Tufts, 1993 -- 1994; UP027.001.00041 (Box 1)
  - Tufts Today: Prospective Students, 1993 -- 1995; UP027.001.00042 (Box 1)
  - Exploring Tufts: A visitor's guide, 1995 -- 1996; UP027.001.00043 (Box 1)
  - Tufts University: The Class of 1999, 1995; UP027.001.00044 (Box 1)
  - Tufts: Bulletin of Tufts University, 1996 -- 1997; UP027.001.00045 (Box 1)
  - Tufts, 1996; UP027.001.00046 (Box 1)
  - Tufts University: The Class of 2000, 1996; UP027.001.00047 (Box 1)
  - Tufts: Bulletin of Tufts University, 1998 -- 1999; UP027.001.00048 (Box 1)
  - Tufts, 1998 -- 1999; UP027.001.00049 (Box 1)
  - Tufts: Bulletin of Tufts University, 2000 -- 2001; UP027.001.00050 (Box 1)
  - Tufts: Bulletin of Tufts University, 2001 -- 2002; UP027.001.00051 (Box 1)
  - Tufts: Bulletin of Tufts University, 2002 -- 2003; UP027.001.00052 (Box 1)
  - Tufts: Bulletin of Tufts University, 2003 -- 2004; UP027.001.00053 (Box 1)
  - Tufts University Viewbook, 2006 -- 2007; UP027.001.00054 (Box 1)
  - Tufts University Viewbook, 2007 -- 2008; UP027.001.00055 (Box 1)
  - Tufts University Viewbook, 2008 -- 2009; UP027.001.00056 (Box 1)
  - Jumbo, November 11, 2011; UP027.001.00057 (Box 1)
    Issue
    1
  - Jumbo, April 1, 2012; UP027.001.00058 (Box 1)
    2
  - Jumbo, Summer, 2012; UP027.001.00059 (Box 1)
    3
  - Jumbo, Fall, 2012; UP027.001.00060 (Box 1)
    4
  - Jumbo, Spring, 2013; UP027.001.00061 (Box 1)
    5
  - Jumbo, Summer, 2013; UP027.001.00062 (Box 1)
    6
  - Jumbo, Fall, 2013; UP027.001.00063 (Box 1)
    7
  - Jumbo, Spring, 2014; UP027.001.00064 (Box 1)
    8
  - Jumbo, Summer, 2014; UP027.001.00065 (Box 1)
    9
  - Jumbo Engineer, 2014; UP027.001.00066 (Box 1)
  - Jumbo, Fall, 2014; UP027.001.00067 (Box 1)
    10
  - Tufts University Welcome, 2014; UP027.001.00068 (Box 1)
    Pamphlet with statistics on admitted students, enrolling students, academics, and student life. Map included.
  - Jumbo Engineer, 2015; UP027.001.00069 (Box 1)
  - Tufts University Welcome, 2015; UP027.001.00072 (Box 1)
  - Jumbo, Spring, 2015; UP027.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
    International Research, How to pick the right school for you, Class highlight, Division III National Champs, Home Away from Home
    11
  - Jumbo, Summer, 2015; UP027.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
    Summer plans, dual degree program with NEC, admissions advice
  - Jumbo, Fall, 2015; UP027.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
    Choosing courses, engineering research, dorm life, SMFA combined degree program
    13
  - Jumbo Engineer, 2015; UP027.001.002.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Jumbo, Spring, 2016; UP027.001.002.00005; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    14
  - Jumbo, Summer, 2016; UP027.001.002.00006 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    15
  - Jumbo, Spring 2017; UP027.001.002.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 7)
    17
  - Jumbo Engineer, 2017; UP027.001.002.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2)
  - Jumbo, Fall 2017; UP027.001.002.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2)
  - Jumbo, Summer 2018; UP027.001.002.00010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Jumbo Engineer, 2018; UP027.001.002.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Jumbo, Fall 2018; UP027.001.002.00013; 1 Folder(s)
  - Jumbo, Spring 2018; UP027.001.002.00014; 1 Folder(s)
    20
  - Tufts 1+4 Bridge Year Service Learning Program, 2018; UP027.001.002.00015; 1 Folder(s)
  - Jumbo, Spring 2019; UP027.000115; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Jumbo, Summer 2019; UP027.000116; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Jumbo, Fall 2019; UP027.000117; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Graduate School of Arts and Sciences, 1987 -- 2018; 1987 -- 2001; UP027.002; 1.2 Linear Feet
  This series contains admissions bulletins printed for prospective Tufts School of Arts and Sciences graduate students, and Continuing and Professional studies. Publications can include school information and highlights, department listing, admissions procedures and requirements, financial aid information, school maps, and application.
  - Tufts University: Graduate Study at the School of Arts and Sciences, 1987 -- 1988; UP027.002.00001 (Box 1)
  - Tufts: Graduate School of Arts and Sciences, Admissions Application, 1991; UP027.002.00002 (Box 1)
  - Tufts: Graduate School of Arts and Sciences, Admissions Application, 1992; UP027.002.00003 (Box 1)
  - Tufts: Graduate School of Arts and Sciences, Admissions Information and Application, 1994; UP027.002.00004 (Box 1)
  - Tufts: Professional and Continuing Studies, 1994 -- 1995; UP027.002.00005 (Box 1)
  - Tufts: Graduate School of Arts and Sciences, 1996; UP027.002.00006 (Box 1)
  - Tufts: Graduate School of Arts and Sciences, 1997; UP027.002.00007 (Box 1)
  - Tufts University: Professional and Continuing Studies, 1999 -- 2000; UP027.002.00008 (Box 1)
  - Tufts University: Graduate School of Arts and Sciences, 2000; UP027.002.00009 (Box 1)
  - Tufts: Graduate and Professional Studies, 2001; UP027.002.00010 (Box 1)
  - Tufts: Gradute School of Arts and Sciences, 2004; UP027.002.00011 (Box 1)
  - Tufts: Graduate School of Arts and Sciences, 2018; UP027.002.00012 (Box 1)
- School of Dental Medicine, 1981 -- 2003; UP027.003; 0.55 Linear Feet
  This series contains admissions bulletins printed for prospective Tufts School of Dental Medicine students. Publications can include school information and highlights, admissions procedures and requirements, financial aid information, school maps, and application.
  - Tufts University School of Dental Medicine: Admissions Prospectus, 1981; UP027.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - Tufts University School of Dental Medicine: Admissions Prospectus, 1982; UP027.003.00002 (Box 3)
  - Tufts University School of Dental Medicine: Division of Advanced Education, General Information, 1985 -- 1986; UP027.003.00003 (Box 3)
  - Tufts University School of Dental Medicine: Division of Advanced Education, General Information, 1987 -- 1988; UP027.003.00004 (Box 3)
  - Tufts School of Dental Medicine: Division of Advanced Education, General Information, 1988 -- 1989; UP027.003.00005 (Box 3)
  - Tufts School of Dental Medicine: Division of Advanced Education, General Information, 1989 -- 1990; UP027.003.00006 (Box 3)
  - Tufts: School of Dental Medicine, Division of Advanced Education, Admissions, 1991 -- 1992; UP027.003.00007 (Box 3)
  - Tufts: School of Dental Medicine, Admissions Information and Application, 1991 -- 1993; UP027.003.00008 (Box 3)
  - Tufts: School of Dental Medicine, Division of Advanced Education, Admissions Information and Application Forms, 1993 -- 1994; UP027.003.00009 (Box 3)
  - Tufts University School of Dental Medicine, Admissions Information and Application Forms, 1996 -- 1997; UP027.003.00010 (Box 3)
  - Tufts University School of Dental Medicine, 2001 -- 2003; UP027.003.00011 (Box 3)
- Graduate School of Engineering, 2018; UP027.004; 1 Folder(s)
  This series contains admissions bulletins printed for prospective Tufts School of Engineering graduate students. Publications can include school information and highlights, admissions procedures and requirements, financial aid information, school maps, and application.
  - Engineering Graduate Programs, 2018; UP027.004.00001 (Box 3)